[Music]
Welcome back. You're with us on Bazar
Morning Call and as we've been telling
you cues across global markets have
turned a little challenging uh because
of the slide that we're seeing on Wall
Street futures and most of the Asian
markets are also in the red. Hong Kong
down about 2% now, Japan's down about a
percent or so. Let's pull up the implied
open. Uh the last time we checked, it
was suggesting that we'll start probably
60 to 65 points lower. Uh yeah, still
around that level, 53 points. Actually,
a little better off. So, let's see.
Promises to be slightly more volatile
than yesterday, at least at the start.
Now, what about individual stocks? Well,
let's straight away get to our team um
which is standing by with the CNBC TV18
list of top stocks to watch for the day.
Guys, morning to all of you. Uh Ru,
let's kick it off with Innocent Bank. So
the this external committee has has
finally you know gave it given its uh
sense on the derivative discrepancies.
What's the latest?
Well yes uh sur good morning. Indent
bank has finally received that PWC
report on discrepancies and that pegs
the hit at 1979 crores which is actually
slightly below street estimates and we
understand broadly in line with RBI's
initial assessment as well and the bank
has now revised the impact to 2.27% 27%
of its December net worth post tax and
will reflect it in its FI25 financials.
So no ugly surprises on that front which
is positive. But the concern is the
delay in disclosure and accounting
discrepancies that may have larger
consequences because we understand at
least three senior level exits are
likely including the CEO and the deputy
CEO who oversaw global markets including
the derivatives portfolio. Now the RBI
we understand has also asked the board
to submit the shortlisted CEO names four
to six months before Katpalia's term end
next year. Indent bank however has
denied receiving any such communication
or any management shakeup.
Okay. All right. Thanks a lot for that
Ru. Well let's hop across to Yash. He's
tracking ICA PU as well as Lumbard.
Yash. Well Nigel good morning. So I'm
going with green as far as ICICF
potential is concerned and that uh is
because there has been a very strong
beat and improvement which has come on
the margin front though on one hand the
growth has been a little bit slow. So
new business premium that grew at 14%
coming in at about 7,444 cr rupes total
AP was down 3% retail AP was down 2%.
This is the slow growth on the top line
that I'm talking about. Value of new
business grew by about 2% and margins as
I said a strong beat and improvement
coming there up 120 basis points at
22.7% versus
21.5% street was anticipating a number
of 21.8% it's managed to beat that also
with that number of 22.7%. Also the
stock is down 14% in the last 3 months
because of these two reasons I'm going
with green on ICIC potential life
insurance ICIC Lombard again I'm going
green and that is because the strong you
know performance which has come overall
in their earnings as far as net earn
premium is concerned that grew by 20%
underwriting loss was down 11% at 210 cr
rupees operating profit that was down
26% that was largely because the
investment income saw contraction in the
quarter nothing apart from that combined
ratio was up just about 20 basis points
at 102.5 versus 102.3. So no major
damage being done on the combined ratio
level also and the protection continues
there. Hence I'm going with green as far
as ICA long bar is concerned.
All right. Actually, we have the
management coming up at 9:50. You'll
hear from the Yash, thank you for that.
The uh management Gopal Bales Chandran
will be with us to talk about those
numbers that Yash pointed out. So,
conversation a little later. IGL, MGL
and Adani Total are in focus as well.
Sud is here with details. Good morning.
Morning Pashan. So, first APM gas price
increase and now the APM gas allocation
cut. While the APM gas price increase
announced on 1st of April was as
expected but this allocation cut has
come as a surprise. Government has
announced that APM gas that is
administered price mechanism gas
allocation has been cut by 18% and now
total allocation would reduce to 40%
from the current level of 51%. Remember
in the last one year the reduction has
been almost at 50%. If you in the in
2024 in the beginning of 2024 the
allocation used to be around 80%, now
it's going to be 40%. What do these
companies say? Companies say that this
allocation cut will have an adverse
impact on profitability and that's the
reason I'm going with red for all the
three companies.
Okay. All right. Got that Sudashan. So
we'll keep all of these stocks on our
radar as well. Uh Irida reported numbers
yesterday. Let's go back to Abishek to
figure out how they were. Abishek. uh
well it reported a good set of numbers
in Q4 FI25 but we need to watch out for
their exposure in Jensol engineering
which will be uh in the minds of
investors in trade today. So disperses
are up.5% YI but they are up 73.6%
sequentially the AM growth is healthy at
about 27.8% YI and about 10 and a half%
sequentially. So uh the yield has
actually worked very well for them. They
have got higher yields in this quarter
which has helped the NI growth at about
57.3% YI and about 22% on a sequential
basis. So provisions are up 24 and a
half% quarter on quarter but they have
reported strong bottom line growth of
about 49% YI and about 18% sequentially.
The spreads have improved so far FI25
the spreads are at 2.42% versus 2.16% on
a year-on-year basis and about 2.28% 28%
that they recorded in Q3 FI25. Their
asset quality also improved. Gross pay
ratio is down to 2.45% versus 2.68% in
the previous quarter. So based on
numbers, the numbers look really good.
But sentiments that will weigh on
investors mind is the uh you know
exposure that they have to genol
engineering. Back to you.
Okay. All right. Thanks a lot for that
Abishek. Well, let's hop across to
Sudashan. He's here to tell us about oil
India and Vidanta S. So in the latest
round of auction that has been done
under open acria's licensing policy
vanta's cane oil and gas has received
total seven new blocks and oil India has
secured nine blocks for kane India new
blocks comprised of four onshore and
three shallow water in sashtra and
Mumbai and with this kane's portfolio
increases to total 69 blocks for oil
India six blocks secured as sole
operator and three has come as
consortium partner and with This oil
India's total explodation areas
increases to 1.1 lakh square kilometer
and that is an increase of almost 85% if
you compare against the same uh same
level of last year. So it's going to be
positive for both these companies vanta
and oil India.
All right so thank you very much for
that. I mean the other story of course
which I guess was really dominating
headlines last evening was the story of
genisol. Absolutely shocking details
coming through in that sebi order. Yash
is here to quickly recap some of the
findings. Yash, take it away. Well,
Prashant, the stocks already seen a
damage of as much as 90% in the last one
year. Uh, Sebis come out with an interim
order yesterday. Uh, though it's an
interim order, but the allegations which
have been made and the explanation of
the allegation pretty pretty serious at
this point of time. uh you know just to
summarize the allegation misutilization
and diversion of funds of Gensol in a
fraudulent manner by the promoters of
the company the promoters of Gensol
benefiting from these diverted funds out
of the company and misleading market
regulator Sebi the credit rating
agencies lenders and investors all
through this entire process of doing all
these violations. Uh as far as the order
is concerned what Sebi said is that
Anmol Singh Jagi and Punit Singh Jagi
the two promoters of the company will be
restrained from holding any position of
a director or KMP in Jensol Engineering.
Jensol Engineering Anmol Singh Jagi and
Punit Singh Jagi will be restrained from
buying, selling or trading in securities
directly or indirectly. Also market
regulator will appoint a foreign audit
you know committee which will conduct
this foreign audit and the report will
be submitted within 6 months of this
committee being appointed. Importantly a
stock split was also announced very
recently as far as Jensol is concerned
that will be put on hold immediately.
Okay. All right. Got it. So yeah not
such a great news and um pretty you know
scathing observations and comments
coming in that sebi order. Thank you for
that. Yes. Let's quickly recap our list
of stocks to watch. The ones that have
positive news flow around them are ICIC
approved life insurance, ICIC, Lombard,
Irida, Oil India and Vidanta. Stocks
with negative news flow around them
would be uh IGL, MGL, Adani, Total Gas
and Gen Sol
Engineering. All right, that's the stock
list. Let's go across to Manisha Gupta
with the latest commodity market action.
Manisha, good morning. Morning and thank
you for that. Well, the safe haven
buying clearly continuing in case of
gold with the dollar index now trading
below 100. Gold continues to see further
gains here. We are trading at an
all-time highs yet again above
$3,275 an ounce at this point in time.
There is strong buying whether it's by
ETFs or from the central banks as well
and that clearly has been supportive. So
while gold continues to do very well,
the other commodities not so well in the
Asian markets right now. You have the
crude oil prices which have slipped yet
again to near fouryear lows. The metal
prices after those initial gains also
seem to be now consolidating and some
marginal losses as well. Copper,
aluminum, you know, quarter% on a weaker
side at this point in time as the
markets continue to deal with a lot of
uncertainty when it comes to uh the
tariffs there. I also want to talk about
rubber which is also trading lower. It's
down 4% on a week and the biggest of
declines when you look at uh industrial
agriculture commodities that clearly
comes in from sugar. That one is trading
at a 30 month low. Sugar prices have
declined by 12% in last one month. So
apart from gold everything else in a bit
of a profit taking.
Okay. All right. Got that Manisha.
Thanks very much. We'll take a very
quick break on that note. On the other
side we'll connect with Adrien Moat who
is investor at Hong Kong S and uh an
expert in emerging markets to talk about
the uh volatility and how to navigate
it.
[Music]